Guide to the William Henry Chafe Oral History Collection, 1933-1988 and undated RL.00207
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral histories, 1970-1978; 1
  - Parker, Mrs. Franklin, Undated; 68
    - Mrs. Franklin Parker, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0177)
    - Mrs. Franklin Parker, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0178)
  - Player, Willa, 1977 December 02; 69
    - Dr. Willa Player Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0031)
    - Dr. Willa Player, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Dr. Willa Player, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
  - Politial Materials, Undated; 70
    - Political materials, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Political materials, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0215)
  - Price, Jim, 1977 May 25; 71
    - Jim Price, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0032)
    - Jim Price, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Jim Price, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
    - Jim Price, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0179)
  - Richmond, David, 1972 April 10; 72
    - David Richmond, 1 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0033)
    - David Richmond, 2 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0034)
    - David Richmond, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - David Richmond, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
    - David Richmond, 1 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0180)
    - David Richmond, 2 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0181)
    - David Richmond, 3 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0182)
  - Roach, George, 1972 July 17; 73
    - George Roach, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - George Roach, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
  - Sanford, Terry, Undated; 74
    - Terry Sanford, Side A, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0035)
    - Terry Sanford, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0078)
    - Terry Sanford, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Terry Sanford, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
    - Terry Sanford, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0183)
  - Schenck, David, Undated; 75
    - David Schenck, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0036)
    - David Schenck, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0184)
    - David Schenck, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0185)
  - Seeber, Hal, Undated; 76
    - Hal Seeber, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Hal Seeber, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
  - Simkins, Anna, Undated; 77
    - Anna Simkins, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Anna Simkins, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
  - Simpkins, Dr. and Mrs. George, 1972 July 19; 78
    - Dr. and Mrs. George Simpkins, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Dr. and Mrs. George Simpkins, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
  - Smith, Ben, 1973 June 06; 79
    - Ben Smith, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0037)
    - Ben Smith,transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Ben Smith, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0212)
    - Ben Smith, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0186)
    - Ben Smith, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0187)
  - Smith, Louise, 1979 February 09; 80
    - Louise Smith, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0038)
    - Louise Smith, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Louise Smith, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
    - Louise Smith, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0188)
    - Louise Smith, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0189)
  - Smith, Mary Cash, 1973 July 11; 81
    - Mary Cash Smith, Side A, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0009)
    - Mary Cash Smith, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Mary Cash Smith, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
  - Smith, McNeill, 1973 July 14; 82
    - McNeill Smith, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - McNeill Smith, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
  - Snider, William, 1974 December 19; 83
    - William Snider, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Snider, William, 1976 November 09; 84
    - William Snider, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Snider, William, 1974 December 19, 1976 November 09; 85
    - William Snider, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
  - Stanley, K. "Tony", 1977 October 13; 86
    - Rev. K. "Tony" Stanley, 1 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0039)
    - Rev. K. "Tony" Stanley, 2 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0040)
    - Rev. K. "Tony" Stanley, 1 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0190)
    - Rev. K. "Tony" Stanley, 2 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0191)
    - Rev. K. "Tony" Stanley, 3 of 3, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0192)
  - Stoneburner, Carol, 1974 December 10; 87
    - Carol Stoneburner, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0081)
    - Carol Stoneburner, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Carol Stoneburner, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
  - Tarpley, John, 1977 October 13; 88
    - Dr. John Tarpley, 1 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0041)
    - Dr. John Tarpley, 2 of 2, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0042)
    - Dr.John Tarpley, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0193)
    - Dr. John Tarpley, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0194)
    - Dr. John Tarpley, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0195)
  - Taylor, John and Betsy, 1973 July 07; 89
    - John and Betsy Taylor, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0043)
    - John and Betsy Taylor, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - John and Betsy Taylor, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
    - John and Betsy Taylor, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0196)
  - Thomas, William, Undated; 90
    - William Thomas, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0044)
    - William Thomas, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - William Thomas, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0213)
    - William Thomas, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0197)
  - Trouble in Greensboro, 1970 March; 91
    - Trouble in Greensboro report, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Trouble in Greensboro report, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0215)
  - Troxler, Evelyn, 1973 June 06; 92
    - Evelyn Troxler, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0045)
    - Evelyn Troxler, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Evelyn Troxler, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0214)
    - Evelyn Troxler, 1 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0198)
    - Evelyn Troxler, 2 of 2, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0199)
  - Troxler, Kay, 1974 October 15; 93
    - Kay Troxler, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0200)
  - Weaver, Mike, 1977 July 06; 94
    - Mike Weaver, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0046)
    - Mike Weaver, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Mike Weaver, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0214)
    - Mike Weaver, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0201)
  - YMCA workshop, Undated; 95
    - Chafe's YMCA workshop, Side B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0077)
  - Zane, Edward R., 1974 September 05; 96
    - Edward R. Zane, Side A and B, audiocassette original (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL00207-CS-0047)
    - Edward R. Zane, transcripts and notes (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Edward R. Zane, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Data-cd RL00207-CD-0214)
    - Edward R. Zane, 1 of 1, compact disc use copy (Box 10, Audio-cd RL00207-CD-0202)
- Writings and Research Series, 1956-1988 and undated; 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Roughly one-half of this series consists of Chafe's notes for Civilities and Civil Rights: Greensboro, North Carolina, and the Black Struggle for Freedom. Notes are divided by chapter. Also included in this series are photocopies of the Federal Bureau of Investigation's Counter Intelligence Program documents pertaining to Black Panther Party members and chapters in Charlotte, N.C. and Oakland, C.A. Series includes reports and writings by others related to Chafe's book, a number of newspaper clippings, two interview transcripts of Ella Baker conducted by Sue Thrasher and Casey Hayden, and information on Civil Rights protests in Durham, Chapel Hill, Greensboro, and the campuses of North Carolina Central University and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.
  - Chapter 2 notes, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Chapter 3 notes, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Chapter 4 notes, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Chapter 5 notes, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Chapter 7 notes (Box 3)
  - Chapter 8 notes, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Black Panther Party COINTELPRO documents, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - COINTELPRO Report on Counterorientation Week at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1969 (Box 3)
  - North Carolina Central University activism, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
  - Chapel Hill Civil Rights Movement oral history interviews, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Research Triangle Civil Right chronolgical list, undated (Box 3)
  - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.'s speech at White Rock Baptist Church, Durham, 1960 Feb. 16 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings on the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 1968-1977 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Mayor's Committee on Human Relations, Durham, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Greensboro Mens Club: Four Decades, 1970 (Box 3)
  - The People of Guilford: Growth and Changes in the Population of Guilford County, 1972 (Box 3)
  - The Role of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare in the Desegregation of the Greensboro, N.C. School System, Julie Buttenwieser, 1988 (Box 3)
  - School Desegregation in Greensboro, 1954-1971, 1971 (Box 3)
  - So Much History, So Much Future: Martin Luther King, Jr. and the Second Coming of America, Vincent Harding, 1979 (Box 3)
  - The Solicitor General's Office, Justice Frankfurter and Civil Rights Litigation, 1946-1960: An Oral History, Philip Elman, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Urbanization, Employment, and Race Relations in Greensboro, North Carolina, 1870-1910, Samuel M. Kipp, III, undated (Box 3)
  - Ella Baker interview transcripts and notes, 1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Adele Clark oral history transcript, 1964 Feb. 28 (Box 3)
  - Notes on the Edward R. Zane Papers, undated (Box 3)
  - Notes on the Greensboro Community Fellowship Papers, undated (Box 3)
  - Simkins v. Cone Hospital United States District Court decision, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Oral history notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - Oral History Project Status Updates, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Chapel Hill Oral History Conference, 1974 and Undated (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Papers Written by Chapel Hill Conferees, 1974 (Box 4)
  - JD Tarpley Biography, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Frank McCain Questions, undated (Box 4)
  - Foster Materials-Desegregation, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Governor Luther Hodges Papers, 1955 and Undated (Box 4)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1954-1957 (Box 4)
  - Southern Regional Council: Emory Via's Field Trip to Greensboro, undated (Box 4)
  - Daily News Coverage of King Death, 1968 April 1 (Box 4)
  - Ku Klux Klan News Articles 1974, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Ku Klux Klan Meetings 1957-58, 1958-1977 (Box 4)
  - Documents for William Chafe, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Chapter 1 notes: Black Community 1930-1954, undated (Box 4)
  - Chapter 1 notes: Kipp and Early History, undated (Box 4)
  - Benjamin Muse Memo in Sit-Ins, 1960 March 8 (Box 4)
  - School Desegregation Clippings: 1963-1970, 1957-1964 (Box 4)
  - Oral History Papers, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Research Notes on Greensboro, 1959-1978 and Undated (Box 4)
  - Greensboro Community Fellowship, 1959-1980, 12 folders (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee Archive Notes: Southeast Region, 1977 September 9 (Box 4)
  - Kornegay Papers, 1963-1979 (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Sanford Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Sociological Articles on Race, 1963-1978 and undated (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee Xeroxes, 1956-1960 and undated (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee Papers: Philadelphia, 1953-1958 (Box 4)
  - Hal Sieber Letters and Clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Moore Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Press Clippings, 1959-1963 (Box 4)
  - Press Clippings, 1959-1963 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
  - Press Clippings, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Governor Robert Scott Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - School Board Minutes, 1960 (Box 4)
  - M.A. Thesis on Sit-Ins, undated (Box 5)
  - Summary Notes for 1973 Greensboro Paper at OAH: Books, Census, Paper, 1956-1973 (Box 5)
  - Notes for SHA Sit-In Paper, undated (Box 5)
  - Early Draft of Sit-In with Goodwyn Comments, undated (Box 5)
  - Gerda Lerner Papers, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1987, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Inventory of Files, undated (Box 5)
  - Chapter 3, undated (Box 5)
  - Chapter 4: The Continuing Struggle, undated, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Chapter 5, undated (Box 5)
  - Draft of Chapter 6, undated (Box 5)
  - Epilogue, undated (Box 5)
  - Pearsall Plan Thesis, 1977 and undated (Box 5)
  - Paper on Sit-Ins as Delivered, undated (Box 5)
  - Bill Lucas Paper on School Desegregation, undated (Box 5)
  - Kipp Dissertation Xeroxes, undated (Box 5)
  - Kipp Dissertation Notes, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Marian Stroble "Pearsall Plan," 1973 (Box 5)
  - Tom Noland "Brown Decision," 1972 (Box 5)
  - Leuchtenburg Comment on Sit-In Article, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Comments on 1974 Organization of American Historians Paper, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Greensboro Names, 1971 and undated (Box 5)
  - Greensboro Bibliography, 1960-1966 and undated (Box 5)
  - Summary Notes on Early Interviews: Names, undated (Box 5)
  - Greensboro National Endowment for the Humanities Application, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Chapter 1, undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1987 and undated (Box 5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Application, undated (Box 5)
  - John Thorner Paper on Press Coverage of Sit-Ins, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Bernadine Moses Thesis on Carolina Peacemaker, undated (Box 5)
  - Organization of American Historians Greensboro Paper,1973 (Box 5)
  - ID Newby Black Carolinians, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, 1987 (Box 5)
  - References, 1985-1987 (Box 6)
  - Chafe Letters, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Dolores Sullivan, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Tax Returns, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Itineraries, 1980-1986 (Box 6)
  - ICA and European Trip, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - University Publications of America, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Oral History Book Manuscript, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Kennedy Library Material, undated (Box 6)
  - Women in Higher Education, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Asheville Speech: Family, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clips, 1975-1976 and Undated (Box 6)
  - Tom Norton "Worker Dissent," undated (Box 6)
  - Ronnie Dugger, undated (Box 6)
  - Daniel Levine: Conservatism and Tradition in Danish Social Welfare Legislation, undated (Box 6)
  - Student Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Violence in Family Material, undated (Box 6)
  - Carolina Peacemaker, undated (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973-1977 and undated (Box 6)
  - Notes for Chapter 8, 1963-1977 and undated, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Benjamin L Smith Papers, 1956 and undated (Box 6)
- Photographs Series, undated; 1 box
  Series consists of 14 photographs located in the final folder of box 3. Photographs show Civil Rights demonstrators, law enforcement response, race relations in the South, and active protest. All photographs are undated with little information regarding subjects and locations, though three photographs are identifiably of Chapel Hill demonstrations.
  - Photographs (Box 3)